I've been using Hermes Agent since the
beginning and last few weeks I realized
I've been using it all wrong. You see
people try to compare Hermes Agent to
Claude or Codex like it's meant to do
the same thing and I truly believed and
wanted Hermes Agent to replace those two
so that they can build apps, build
systems, build content inside of Hermes
and not touch Claude or Codex anymore
other than the models from them. And it
absolutely can do all those things, but
as we can see here it's slower and less
token efficient than Claude or Codex in
building apps or internal tools or
systems. So these days I prefer to use
Hermes as an operator or AI employee
within the system that I build with
Claude or Codex. That's why in this
video I wanted to show you my favorite
15 Hermes Agent use cases that I found
that I use personally in my life or
business and how you can apply them to
your business and using these ideas and
principles. And before we go into that,
let me just show you what I'm working on
right now. So this is something I'm
working on and testing for our business
Press Wiz. I'm building this CLI that
can connect your agent to the
marketplace and order backlinks on your
behalf so you don't have to search
and order yourself. The agent can do all
of that on your behalf.
So that's the idea. I'm still testing
this, but this is the example where I
would be using
Codex and not Hermes to build this and
to test this. And Hermes can operate
this CLI and order backlinks for me, but
I wouldn't be using Hermes to build this
actual project. So this covers this
example and let's go back to my favorite
use cases for Hermes Agent. So these are
the 15 ones I use regularly. Some of
these are still in testing, but most of
them I use every day. And if you want
more ideas, you can find a ton of them
here on News Research website.
And you can just browse and get ideas
how people are using Hermes Agent. So,
going back here, SEO Analyst is
something that I'm currently mostly
testing. It's still not live. It's still
not implemented fully.
And it gives the agent access to Search
Console and Ahrefs, Semrush, whatever
you want. And you can go and search on
your console and then create a report
and then also search the web and get
Ahrefs APIs about your competitors and
so on and then create a comprehensive
either a report or actually take action
on those things itself. Lead Scraper
Agent is next and uses Apify, Far Crawl,
Serper, or Clay to find and enrich
leads. And we use that for outbound in
Press Release as well.
And I'm going to show you how the output
looks. It's basically a CSV file
with a bunch of leads. I'll mask these
for privacy, but yeah, essentially
like this found 2,000
SEO agencies, which are ICP. And we then
enrich them using Clay and using AnyMail
Finder and these various tools to find
emails, to find LinkedIns, and so on.
And then we can do
instantly,
which sends via MCP
all the emails.
Or we have a custom integration that
does LinkedIn.
So, that's a really useful one if you do
outbound.
Sales CRM, in my previous video, I'm
going to link it somewhere above,
I used Hermes Agent to connect to my
HighLevel CRM and to do inbox
email inbox triage,
create notes about clients, research
clients that come in, and
basically create reports or whatever we
need from the CRM, we can just ask the
agent and it can create the report for
us.
Sales call analyst, this is something we
are implementing right now, but
basically taking all the transcripts
automatically after the call, it
generates a transcript, it sends it to
the agent, and then the agent can create
next steps and tasks within the CRM for
our staff. The next one is the research
agent, and I'm using that every day. It
creates a summary for me what's new on
social media, on X, on YouTube. So, I
don't have to go and doom scroll for 1
hour just to find out what's been going
on, and it follows Claude, Codex,
news research, whatever, just to get me
the things that interest me, and the
beauty of it is it's self-improving, so
that when I rate the results, it comes
up with better results
the next day. And this is how it looks.
So, basically every day I receive
one message like this,
and it's all the stuff that interests me
about AI, X. So, I don't have to go and
doom scroll
all the time. So, this is still
improving, obviously, and as time goes
on, I'll only get the stuff that really,
really interests me. Next, we have the
content producer. So, if let's say I
spot a news about, let's say Hermes
agent, I can send this to my Hermes
agent, and then it creates the idea for
a video. That's kind of how I came up
with this. I saw the blog post here,
and I sent it to my agent, and we worked
out an idea for this video, how we can
create this. So, it it adjusts the
sources, and it creates the package or
outline or scripts, whatever you need,
thumbnails even.
Re-purposing, once the video is
finished, you can create newsletters,
blog posts, LinkedIn posts, X posts, and
so on. I'm still not using this fully
and still testing a lot of moving parts
here. Second brain, the thing everybody
likes.
So, I'm using Notebook LM and I've made
videos previously about Notebook LM and
Councils.
And Notebook LM is just my preferred
tool. Obsidian, I've only briefly
tested, everyone loves it.
I will give it a try, I promise, and
then I will report back.
And Pinecone is a bit more advanced,
it's a database. So, it's a whole
different video.
Here, we have the executive assistant.
So, it's straightforward pretty much,
you give it access to your inbox,
calendar, tasks, meetings, notes, and it
can just help you out, triage,
tell you what's on your schedule, so you
don't miss a meeting or things like
that, and to
tell it what happened in the meeting and
it can create notes for you, pretty easy
to understand.
Business analyst, of course, depending
on your business, you would have
different Excel sheets, dashboards,
whatever you can imagine, just point
your agent there. If you have the MCP or
CLI connected there, give it access, and
it can create wonderful reports, and it
can monitor things for you, and yeah,
just figure out how you can give it
access to things. Obviously, scope it so
that you don't give it sensitive
information.
And
we have operations employee here, any
recurring workflow, process, checklist,
monitoring,
it can do that for you, and it has a
cron job, you can schedule it on a
recurring basis, so it's really good
at that. This is a bit generic, but
depending on your business, this can be
applied differently.
Customer support, this is great. So, for
e-commerce, for example, you can
set it to monitor tickets, to answer
tickets, to escalate tickets. Very good
for customer support.
Shopify actually has both the API and an
MCP. So, you can definitely connect your
agent there. And like my example about
the CRM, it can create reports. You can
ask it, "Hey, how many orders we had
today?" It can check for you and report
back. So, you don't have to log in to
Shopify.
This is just one example, but anything
that you can read on the dashboard, the
agent can read as well. So, you can see
how that powerful that can be.
And now we come to one of my favorite
use cases, and this is the investment
analyst.
So, basically, how I use it is I give it
a list of stocks, and it goes through my
preferred sources to investigate and to
get data, up-to-date data.
So, it crawls everything with Firecrawl,
and then comes back with aggregated
result, and it gives me advice and
summary about what's going on, how are
the earnings, and so on. So, it looks
like this.
Obviously, it's called Warren, my
investment analyst. Yeah, I just give it
a bunch of stocks to research, and I
don't know why this gold here is, but
yeah, it probably had some context left
over.
And yeah, it said that Microsoft is the
best. I'm not going to argue with this.
It's just
one example how you can use this agent.
It also has my portfolio tracker that I
created with Cloud and Codex. And now
this agent can use the portfolio
tracker. I just send it a screenshot
when I make a trade, and it
automatically logs everything into the
portfolio tracker, which has now
everything I need, including options
tracking.
Which is something I was missing with
all the these other
portfolio trackers.
Okay, and then the last we have the
advisory council. And I actually made a
video previously about the Notebook LM
advisory council. The idea is to
populate notebooks with YouTube videos,
books, interviews, transcripts of
your favorite
It can be a YouTuber, it can be an
influencer, or a writer.
And then you can query Notebook LM about
their knowledge and to actually get
context out of this material
so that you can use it in Cloud. And
I'll just show you briefly
how this looks. Notebook LM
council. One second.
So, let's say which
use cases would
Tony Robbins and Alex Hormozi have
for Hermes agent.
And then we can wait and see the result.
So, we'll just pause this video so you
can actually see how this works. And it
comes back with results from Tony
Robbins and Alex Hormozi. And Tony said
event intelligence engine. You can see
how this context works because Tony is
in events.
Personalized coaching.
Yeah, and you can see sales call
intelligence, obviously, we mentioned
that.
Offer optimization agent, great.
Content repurposing, great, yeah.
Customer proof flywheel. Yeah,
absolutely.
So,
this wraps it up, honestly, for this
video. You can see the power of Hermes
agent. I'll show you my personal use
cases that I'm using everyday. And just
think about it and see how you can apply
it to your business. Find a bottleneck,
find something that takes your time,
even if it's scrolling through social
media. You can automate that so that you
can get
more
for your time
with Hermes Agent. Let me know in the
comments, have you found any interesting
use cases for Hermes Agent? And please
subscribe and like the video if you
liked it. And if you have any issues or
questions, feel free to post below.
Thank you.